Guide to the School of Art, Yale University, Lectures and Presentations
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Art, Yale University, lectures and presentations
1963-1991
RU 1083
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(26 boxes)
The materials consist of audiorecordings of lectures and presentations at the Yale School of Art.
Yale University. School of Art
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 20-H (YRG 20-H), Audio-visual materials and memorabilia documenting the Yale School of Art
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the School of Art, 2008
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audiorecordings of lectures and presentations at the Yale School of Art
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically
Art schools; Art -- Study and teaching; Lectures and lecturing; Audiotapes; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University. School of Art
- Lectures and presentations [audiorecordings], 1985-1991; Accession 2008-A-185
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Wollheim, Richard
    - "What the Spectator Sees", 1985 April 17; 1 (Box 1)
    - "Painting: Textuality and Borrowing: Poussin, Manet and Picasso", 1985 April 18; 1 (Box 2)
    - "Painting: Omnipotence and the Gaze: Ingres, The Wolf Man and Picasso", 1985 April 19; 1 (Box 3)
  - Berthot, Jake, "Speaking on His Own Work at Norfolk", 1987 June 16; 1 (Box 4)
  - Ryan, Richard, "Speaking on His Own Work at the Yale Summer School of Art at Norfolk", 1987 June 19; 2 (Box 5–6)
  - Smith, Don, "On Edward Dickinson", 1987 June 23; 2 (Box 7–8)
  - Anderson, Lennard, 1987 June 29; 1 (Box 9)
  - Kury, Gloria, 1987 July 15; 1 (Box 10)
  - Koons, Jeff and Ron Jones, "Conversations at Yale", 1991 April 1; 1 (Box 11)
  - Holzer, Jenny, R. Jones, and R. Flood, 1991 April 22; 1 (Box 12)
  - McEvilley, Thomas, 1991 November 5; 2 (Box 13–14)
  - Sommer, Frederick, 1991 November 18; 1 (Box 15)
  - McEvilley, Thomas
    - 1991 Nov 19, 2 (Box 16–17)
    - 1991 Dec 3, 3 (Box 18–20)
    - 1991 Dec 10, 2 (Box 21–22)
    - 1991 Dec 12, 2 (Box 23–24)
    - 1991 Dec 17, 2 (Box 25–26)
- Art and Architecture Lecture Series, 1963-1977, undated; Accession 19ND-A-504
  - Dickinson, Edwin and Louis Finklestein, 1963 November 13; 2 (Box 1–2)
  - Holtzman, Harry, 206 AA
    - 1966 February 22, 1 (Box 3)
    - 1966 March 1, 2 (Box 4–5)
    - 1966 March 8, 1 (Box 6)
  - Lumet, Sidney
    - 1973 February 7, 1 (Box 7)
    - 1973 February 14, 2 (Box 8–9)
    - 1973 March 14, 2 (Box 10–11)
  - Rossellini, Roberto
    - Discussion after Louis XIV, 1974 January 22; 1 (Box 12)
    - 1974 January 29, 2 (Box 27–28)
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 27U, Box 28Ua)
    - 1974 February 26, 1 (Box 28)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 28Ub)
  - Eames, Charles, special, 1974 February 7; 1 (Box 13)
  - Keller, Joan, course
    - Leacock, Richard, 1974 January 24; 2 (Box 14–15)
    - Perry, Frank, 1974 February 14; 2 (Box 16–17)
    - Guggenheim, Charles, 1974 February 21; 2 (Box 18–19)
    - Brandy in the Wilderness, 1974 March 7; 1 (Box 20)
    - Malick, Terrence, Badlands, 1974 March 14; 1 (Box 21)
    - Lawder, Standish, Runaway, Corridor, Dangling Participle, and others, 1974 April 11; 1 (Box 22)
  - HSW talks on MDS, Yale Club of New Haven, 1977 April 4; 1 (Box 23)
  - Geller in class, Undated; 1 (Box 24)
  - Railsbach narration (tails), Tape 2: edited, Undated; 1 (Box 25)
  - Sound effects, 7A, Undated; 1 (Box 26)